[{"answer": "There is to a certain degree simply because if you look at the terms of the ceasefire agreement, at the very least, it does state that Israel must open its border crossings, it needs to facilitate the movement of goods and of people.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 29, "question": "Arwa, how is the atmosphere like in Gaza and is there a sense that Hamas has strengthened its position through the last eight or nine days?", "qSentId": 28}, {"answer": "Well, on the one hand, one needs to remember that when it came to trying to mediate deals between these two sides, Egypt has always played something of a pretty critical and central role.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 36, "question": "How significant is the fact that Egypt appears to be calling the shots in terms of the way that the Palestinians are reacting?", "qSentId": 35}, {"answer": "It is an arrangement that has been negotiated with Egypt and with the support of the United States.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 46, "question": "Can you outline exactly what you believe the spirit of this agreement to be today?", "qSentId": 45}, {"answer": "You know, if Hamas changed, if Hamas moderated its positions, if Hamas met the three benchmarks that were articulated by the United Nations, that is recognizing my country's right to exist, abandoning terrorism and violence, supporting peace, then the door is open to negotiations.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 66, "question": "Do you see any parallel there and do you see a time when Hamas will be seen as a legitimate body by Israel?", "qSentId": 65}, {"answer": "No, I think I hope the Americans will not fall into another mistake.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 91, "question": "How much of a concern is it to you that Mahmoud Abbas had very little to do with this ceasefire being broken, in fact nothing, we understand?", "qSentId": 90}, {"answer": "President Abbas was not absent from all these negotiations.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 98, "question": "So are you personally concerned that all the dealings here appear to have been done directly with Hamas and not with a wider group to include President Abbas?", "qSentId": 97}, {"answer": "Well, he was talking about eventual recognition of the state of Israel because that's what everybody wants to know about the Palestinian.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 144, "question": "Christiane, what did you make of your interview with Khaled Meshaal, and in particular, the way he defined how a possible peace settlement could unravel here?", "qSentId": 143}, {"answer": "I want to read you a tweet from a mutual friend of ours.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 180, "question": "How are you, Piers?", "qSentId": 179}, {"answer": "I don't.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 184, "question": "Do you know who wrote that?", "qSentId": 183}, {"answer": "I don't see how or why you would be critical of a ceasefire.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 193, "question": "How do you view the president's time the last few days?", "qSentId": 192}, {"answer": "Right.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 228, "question": "What was your view?", "qSentId": 227}, {"answer": "Well, you know, you're preaching to the converted here.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 241, "question": "Would you like to Chris Christie running as a potential president in 2016?", "qSentId": 240}, {"answer": "It's rather actually a very hard time for us, all of us.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 260, "question": "What has life been like for you in Gaza over the last eight or nine days?", "qSentId": 259}, {"answer": "It's been very difficult eight days in (INAUDIBLE).", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 273, "question": "What is your view?", "qSentId": 272}, {"answer": "I mean, I'm sure that she's facing a difficult reality, but I don't want to get into politics because, you know, we are just civilians and I can feel her story, you know, as I new mother I can relate to her story as well.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 291, "question": "What would you say to her as a young Israeli woman to a young Palestinian woman?", "qSentId": 290}, {"answer": "Yes, I agree with her, the first part that we're both mothers and we are civilians, and we don't want to involve in the political issue.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 300, "question": "What would you say, Ameera, in response to what Natalie said there?", "qSentId": 299}, {"answer": "What I get from talking to both of you is that -- is that when you cut away from all the politics and from military wings of both these political sides, what you are left with are real people living in very, very difficult situations, and the most important thing now is the ceasefire holds and that the people who've been responsible for all these rockets and missiles get together around the negotiating table and bring both of you a better life where you don't have to worry about what happens to your young children every day or young children that belong to your friends and relative.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 309, "question": "So I don't know how I can teach her, you know, the meaning of life to be a normal kid, to live under, you know, peaceful time, while she is growing up under attack (INAUDIBLE), you know?", "qSentId": 308}, {"answer": "The human aspect is very, very touching without a doubt.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 321, "question": "What did you make of what they said?", "qSentId": 320}, {"answer": "What we saw in Northern Ireland was a two-track process.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 330, "question": "Do you think it's inevitable and is it almost essential that the same process now happens with Hamas, given, as you say, that so many Palestinians and so many Arab countries around Israel believe that it is an elected body and should be legitimized?", "qSentId": 329}, {"answer": "Well, one thing that's really important to remember is that, you know, I think that Netanyahu has an election coming up in January, so, you know, in our election, he kind of bet on the wrong course.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 371, "question": "What do you think of the way this is now playing out for Obama, for his presidency, for the Democrats and for their strategy in the Middle East?", "qSentId": 370}, {"answer": "I think to an extent.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 376, "question": "Kristen Soltis, do you agree with that?", "qSentId": 375}, {"answer": "I absolutely do believe that.", "docId": "121121pmt", "aSentId": 387, "question": "Charles, are you getting the same feeling that I am, that there is a more collective will to try and avoid falling off this cliff and to get a deal done perhaps sooner rather than later?", "qSentId": 386}]